hey guys I made this video the other day
and I showed a shortcut to solve it a
bunch of people asked me to solve it the
hyper complicated way so let's do it so
it gives us some links here and it wants
to know what is the length of a b so
first let's find this length right here
this is a right triangle so if we call
this side C we can use Pythagorean
theorem we have 2 squared plus 4 squared
equals c squared 2 squared is four four
squared is sixteen four plus sixteen is
twenty and after we square root both
sides we get C is equal to square root
of 20. so let's change the C into square
root of 20. so next let's find this side
let's call it C and we could do 2
squared plus 2 squared equals c squared
both of these two squareds are four four
plus four is eight and we could square
root both sides to get C is equal to the
square root of eight and the exact same
thing is going to happen right here so
this will also be square root of 8.
let's focus our energy right here in
fact enhance let's focus our energy
right here this is a 90 degree angle
this right here is an isosceles right
triangle which means that's 45 degrees
and then for this last angle there's no
shortcut so let's call it d degrees and
let's use some trigonometry we know that
the tangent of D is equal to the
opposite over the adjacent well this
opposite side is 4 and the adjacent side
is 2 so this is going to become four
over two and four over two is equal to
2. then we can tangent inverse both
sides on the left hand side we have D
and it'll be equal to the tangent
inverse of two which is approximately
63.4 degrees so let's change this D to
63.4 degrees now we can get this last
angle let's call it n all four of these
will add up to 360. we can combine the
45 to 90 and the 63.4 to give us 198.4
after we subtract 198.4 from both sides
we get n is equal to 161.6 so let's
change that that was good so we can zoom
back out now we can connect this last
side and focus on this triangle right
here so this side right here is made up
of 2 square root of eights so let's call
it 2 square root of 8. this side is root
20 and this side is unknown let's call
the unknown side C and in fact this
unknown side is the a b that we wanted
to solve from before or so we're going
to use a thing called law of cosines
here it is right here you'll recognize a
portion of it as a squared plus b
squared equals c squared that's the
Pythagorean theorem but since it's not a
right triangle we have this little extra
portion so for both of these A's I'm
going to plug in 2 square root of 8 and
for both of these B's I'm going to plug
in square root of 20. and then for this
angle Theta we're going to plug in 161.6
this Square goes to both the 2 and the
square root of 8. 2 squared is equal to
4 and square root of 8 squared is equal
to 8 and then 4 times 8 is equal to 32
and then square root of 20 squared will
give us 20. next we can plug all of this
stuff into a calculator and it will give
us a negative 48. there it is right
there and then minus negative 48 is
positive 48 and 32 plus 20 plus 48 is
equal to 100 and after we square root
both sides we get C is equal to 10. so
we can update this C to be 10. and then
returning back to the original problem
we have that right here the C is equal
to 10. how exciting